The incredible story of the team that changed the game forever.
Glory Road is a drama, history film directed by James Gartner.
In 1966, Texas Western coach Don Haskins led the first all-black starting line-up
for a college basketball team to the NCAA national championship.
Don Haskins, played by Josh Lucas.
Bobby Joe Hill, played by Derek Luke.
Adolph Rupp, played by Jon Voight.
Jerry Armstrong, played by Austin Nichols.
Moe Iba, played by Evan Jones.
Harry Flournoy, played by Mehcad Brooks.
Glory Road is a 2006 American sports drama film directed by James Gartner, based on a true story
surrounding the events leading to the 1966 NCAA University Division Basketball Championship.
Don Haskins portrayed by Josh Lucas, head coach of Texas Western College (now known as University of Texas at
El Paso or UTEP), coached a team with an all-black starting lineup, a first in NCAA history.
Glory Road explores racism, discrimination and student athletics.
Supporting actors Derek Luke and Jon Voight also star in principal roles.
The film was a co-production between the motion picture studios of Walt Disney Pictures,
Jerry Bruckheimer Films, Texas Western Productions, and Glory Road Productions.
It was commercially distributed by Buena Vista Pictures theatrically and by the
Buena Vista Home Entertainment division for the video rental market.
It premiered in theaters nationwide in the United States on January 13, 2006, grossing
$42,938,449 in box office business despite generally mixed reviews from critics.
Glory Road was nominated for a number of awards including the Humanitas
Prize; the film won the 2006 ESPY Award for Best Sports Movie.
On January 10, 2006, the original motion picture soundtrack was
released by the Hollywood Records music label.
The soundtrack was composed and orchestrated by musician Trevor Rabin.
The DVD release, featuring theatrical trailers, extended interviews with players and colleagues of
coach Haskins, and deleted scenes, among other highlights, was released in the U.S.
on June 6, 2006.
The film explores themes of racial segregation, based on
true story, basketball, teachers and students.
The tone is emotional.